沒人相信愛麗絲
No one believed Alice
所說的仙境冒險
when she spoke of her adventures in Wonderland,
她是如何愛上精靈塞勒斯
of how she fell in love with a genie named Cyrus,
紅心王后又是如何拆散他們的
and how the Red Queen tore them apart.
不
No!
愛麗絲  她需要幫助
Alice. She needs help.
所以紅桃杰克和我帶她回了仙境
So the Knave of Hearts and I brought her back to Wonderland
尋找她的真愛
to search for her true love.
他在這里  我能感覺到
He's here. I can feel it.
有人想阻止她
There are those who will try to stop her.
讓那個女孩許下三個愿
What we want can't be accomplished
我們的目的才能達成
until the girl's made all her wishes.
但是愛麗絲的偉大冒險
But Alice's greatest adventure
剛剛開始
has just begun.
《仙境奇緣》前情提要
Previously in Wonderland...
這里怎么了
What happened here?
猛獸來襲過
Bandersnatch attacked.
-你殺了它嗎  -沒有
- Did you kill it? - No.
是個年輕女子  和一個男人
It was a young woman and a man.
這個男人是誰
Who was this man?
她叫他"杰克"
She called him "Knave."
告訴我  杰克  安娜斯塔西婭是誰
So, tell me, Knave, who's Anastasia?
這是個心碎的故事
That is a tale of heartbreak.
我愛你  安娜斯塔西婭
I love you, Anastasia.
我愛你  威爾·史卡利
I love you, Will Scarlet.
阿格拉巴
多年前
男孩
Boy!
男孩  火要滅了
Boy, the fire's dying!
小崽子
Boy!
沒有煤了  我得去...
There was no coal left. I had to go--
不要找借口
No excuses!
我真該把你丟回那條發現你的陰溝
I should throw you back in the gutter where I found you!
不要  求你了
No! Please!
今晚又不想吃飯了是吧
Maybe another night without food
也許這樣能提醒你更好地干活兒
will remind you to be better prepared!
男孩  男孩
Boy! Boy!
轉過來
Turn away!
男孩  她會讓我們原地燒起來的
Boy! She'll burn us where we stand!
抱歉來打擾您
I'm sorry to disturb you.
-我...  -你在集市干活
- I-- - You work at the market.
是的
Yes.
來敲我的門干什么
What are you doing at my door?
我想知道您能不能...
I was wondering if you--
我不是在問你想要什么
I'm not asking what you want.
我是在問你為什么來騷擾我
I'm asking why you'd disturb me.
你一定知道我的能耐
You must know what I can do to you.
對于我即將過上的生活來說
Death would be a kindness
死亡都算是仁慈了
compared to the life I have ahead of me.
我希望您能教我
I want you to teach me.
-教你  -黑魔法
- Teach you? - Dark magic.
這樣有一天  人們就會畏懼我
So that one day people will fear me,
就如他們畏懼你一樣
as they fear you.
不行
No.
求你了  我會替你干活  聽從你的吩咐
Please! I will work for you, do anything you want.
魔法可不只是用來對抗惡棍的
Magic is not something you use to simply fight off bullies.
-我不想...  -那你想怎樣
- That's not what-- - Then what is it?
我想報仇
I want revenge.
對誰
On who?
走吧  男孩  免得我...
Go away, boy, before I turn--
蘇丹王
The Sultan.
為什么像你這樣的人
And why would someone like you
會和蘇丹王扯上關系
have any concern with the Sultan?
因為  他是我父親
Because... he's my father.
是真的嗎
Is this true?
兩個人之間最重要的就是誠信
There's nothing more important between two people than honesty.
在我看來  你可不像皇族
To my eyes, you look nothing like royalty.
他拋棄了我
He abandoned me!
蘇丹王為什么要拋棄自己的親骨肉
Why would the Sultan abandon his own flesh and blood?
因為他說  我是他的私生子
Because, as he says, I am his bastard.
我恨他入骨
I hate him with the fire of a thousand suns!
總算
Finally...
你說實話了
honesty.
你叫什么  男孩
What's your name, boy?
賈法爾
Jafar.
好吧  賈法爾
Well, Jafar,
明天我們來看看你有什么本事
tomorrow we will begin to see what you can do.
美麗至極
Fabulous.
有樣東西叫前門  親愛的
There's a thing called the front door, darling.
你真該試一試
You really must try it sometime.
我覺得秘密見面
I thought making our interactions secret
更合你的意
would be more to your liking.
畢竟  保密是你的習慣
After all, secrets seem to be a habit of yours.
對對的  對對得  你們退下吧
Tweedles, begone, dears.
兩個人之間
There's nothing more important
最重要的
between two people
就是誠信
than honesty.
你不同意嗎
Wouldn't you agree?
什么事
What's this about?
你為什么不告訴我愛麗絲帶了朋友來仙境
Why didn't you tell me Alice brought a friend to Wonderland?
這個紅桃杰克
This Knave of Hearts.
因為這是無關緊要的小細節
'Cause it was an inconsequential detail.
他只不過是個懦弱的小偷
He's nothing but a cowardly thief.
我們無需擔心他
He's of very little concern to us.
其實  他造成了很大的麻煩
Actually, he's caused a great deal of trouble,
要我說  他的出現需要引起大大的重視
so I'd say his presence is of great concern.
你為什么帶他來
Why did you bring him?
因為事情不是
Because it wasn't quite as simple
給愛麗絲送一張邀請函那樣簡單
as sending Alice an invitation.
不然你一個人就能搞定了
Otherwise, you'd have done it yourself.
我需要愛麗絲信任的人
I needed someone that Alice trusted,
這個人剛好就是杰克
and that someone happened to be the Knave.
他起了作用
He served his purpose.
現在他的任務完成了
And now his purpose is done.
正是
Precisely.
那就沒問題了
Then there's no issue.
除掉他
Eliminate him.
把他驅逐出場
Remove him from the playing field.
去找紅心王后是個糟糕的主意  愛麗絲
Going after the Red Queen is a bad idea, Alice.
她偷走了塞勒斯的瓶子
She stole Cyrus' bottle.
唯一合理的解釋就是塞勒斯也在他手上
It only stands to reason that she has Cyrus as well.
所以你打算只身一人去追蹤她的軍隊嗎
So you're gonna go after the entire red army by yourself?
如果有必要的話
If that's what it takes.
-有更聰明的法子  -有嗎
- There's a smarter way to do this. - Is there now?
打出你手上有的牌  愛麗絲
Play the hand you've been dealt, Alice.
我看過你的牌  杰克  沒有幾張
I've seen your cards, Knave, and they're quite lacking.
正是虛張聲勢的時候
Which is exactly the time to start bluffing.
白兔...
Look, the White Rabbit--
他還不知道我們知道他在為王后效力
he has no idea we know he's working for the Queen.
我們得利用這一點
We need to use that to our advantage,
騙他告訴我們塞勒斯在哪里
fool him into telling us where Cyrus is.
或者我們可以提起他的雙腳
Or we could just pick him up by the feet,
把他掛在懸崖邊  直到他告訴我們所知的一切
dangle him over a cliff until he tells us everything he knows.
-你最好別這么一本正經的  -那邊
- We need to work on your poker face. - Over here!
-你聽到了嗎  -聽到了
- Did you hear that? - I did.
有人在跟蹤我們
Oh. Someone's following us.
聽這聲音  看來有不少人
By the sounds of things, I'd say several someones.
你認識他們嗎
Do you recognize them?
是毛蟲的人
They work for the Caterpillar.
-他們是搜捕隊  -我們有什么選擇
- They're collectors. - What are our options?
基本上我們可以去死  也可以逃跑
Well, basically, we could die, or we could run.
我不大喜歡第一種
I don't particularly care for the first one.
我也不喜歡  左邊還是右邊
Me, neither. Left or right?
-左邊  -好
- Left. - Okay.
他去哪里了
Where'd he go?!
快追他
After him!
他逃跑了
He's getting away!
他跑了
Getting away!
他們找的是我  我們該分頭行動
I'm the one they want. We should split up.
我們應該留下來戰斗
We should stay and fight.
更好的主意  你留在這里  我去引開他們
Oh, better idea-- you stay, I go.
這邊
Oi! Over here!
-威爾  不要  -我會沒事的
- Will, no! - I'll be fine.
我對這片森林了如指掌
I know these woods like the back of my hand--
-我沒事  拼圖森林見  -威爾
- I'm fine! Meet you back in Tulgey. - Will!
沒事  塞勒斯  好事多磨
It's okay, Cyrus. This is just a detour.
我們很快就能在一起了
I'll be with you soon.
行行好吧  先生
Please, sir.
-我好幾天沒吃飯了  -你該在犯錯前
- I haven't eaten for days. - You should have thought of that
就想到這一點
before you did whatever it is you did.
你說得對  我犯了十分嚴重的錯誤
You're right. I-I've made some terrible mistakes,
但我餓死了
but I'm starving.
你能不能分我一根骨頭  讓我嘗嘗味道
Could you even just spare a bone? Just a little taste?
看看上面還有沒有肉吧
See if you can find a morsel out of that.
我們被關在這里這么多天
In all the days we've been here together,
我從沒見過你像那樣祈求過任何東西
I've never seen you grovel like that for anything,
更別說是食物了
let alone food.
那是因為我對食物不感興趣
That's because I'm not interested in food.
你想要骨頭嗎
You wanted the bone?
這是一根如愿叉骨
It's a wishbone.
你打算許個愿逃離這里嗎
You're going to wish yourself out of this place?
類似吧
Something like that.
我們一定跟丟了他  你走這邊
We must have missed him! You go this way!
我走后面
I'll go the back!
沿著岸找
Look along the bank!
愛麗絲
Alice?
你真覺得
Did you really think
她有那個能耐  一個人搞定這些嗎
that she could do this all by herself?
該死
Bloody hell.
你好  威爾
Hello, Will.
阿格拉巴
我爬到巖壁下
And so... so I'm scrambling
試圖救他
down the rock face to try and save him,
這只蠢羊看見一叢灌木
when the stupid goat-- he sees a shrub.
還沒鷹嘴豆大
No bigger than a chickpea,
但他就是得吃  他走了一步
but he just has to eat it. He takes one step...
就摔了下去...
down right...
永遠也不能低估
One can never underestimate the stupidity
-山羊的愚蠢和吃貨精神啊  -是啊
- or the appetite of a goat. - Yes.
謝謝你救了他  艾其爾
Well, thanks for saving him, Akil--
盡管他不配
even if he didn't deserve it.
這是我的工作
Well, it is my job.
這袋酒是給你的
We have this wine for you
這是對你辛勞工作的獎賞
as a reward for your good work.
謝謝你  賈法爾
Oh... thank you, Jafar.
請你放心
May you rest easy.
不  還不是時候
No, not yet.
你什么時候才能讓我學習那本書里的咒語
When are you going to let me study the spells inside that book?
等你準備好的時候
When you're ready.
而現在你還沒準備好
Which, as of now, you're not.
不過  是時候該教你
It is, however, time for me to teach you
掩蔽咒語了
the masking spell,
你不是很想學嗎
which you've been so eager to learn.
你不是說過學不了那個咒語的嗎
But I thought you said we couldn't,
因為需要人的肝臟
because it requires a human liver.
確實如此  但你剛剛給弄到一個
It does, but you've just gotten us one.
你給艾其爾的那袋酒...被下過毒
The wine you gave Akil-- it was poisoned.
他馬上就要命喪黃泉了
He'll be dead any moment now.
艾其爾什么都沒做錯
But Akil did nothing!
確實如此
Quite right.
他是個好人
He's a fine man.
這是毒藥的解藥
And this is the antidote to the poison.
如果愿意  你把它可以交給他
If you wish, you can give it to him.
但如果你給了他  我們就沒有人肝了
But if you do, we won't have the liver.
你就不能學咒語了
And you won't be able to learn the spell.
你知道這是什么嗎  賈法爾
Do you know what this is, Jafar?
-一條蛇  -你知道為什么
- A serpent. - Do you know why
我在周圍擺滿這種生物的裝飾嗎
I surrounded myself with such creatures?
不知道
No.
因為它們其中蘊藏的真諦
It is because of their true essence.
它們最重要的能力
Their most important quality--
就是必要之時
that when they need to,
可以蛻皮  重獲新生
they shed their skin and are reborn.
這就是你要做的  賈法爾
And that is what you need to do, Jafar.
放任無辜的人死去嗎
By letting an innocent die?
是向我展示
By showing me
你會不惜一切代價
that you're willing to do whatever's necessary
爭取你想要的東西
to get what you want.
你會嗎
Are you?
還是說  你還是那個
Or are you still just that little boy
來到我門前的
who came to my door,
僅有一腔怒火的小男孩
full of anger but little else?
現在我們知道了
Well, now we know.
祝賀你  賈法爾
Congratulations, Jafar.
你重獲新生了
You are reborn.
大人
Sire?
她抓到他了
She's got him--
紅桃杰克
the knave of hearts.
他們正押送他回宮殿
They're on their way back to the palace.
好極了
Excellent.
還有什么事要我為您效勞嗎
Is there anything else I can do for you?
不了  下面的事就交給我吧
No. I shall take it from here.
記得提醒我獎賞你的好表現
Remind me to reward you for your good work.
當然
Of course.
你不該回仙境來的  威爾
You should never have come back to wonderland, Will.
你的女朋友愛麗絲給了你什么
So what did your girlfriend Alice offer you
這么吸引你  甚至戰勝了你的生存本能
that was enticing enough for you to overcome your survival instincts, hmm?
她不是我的女朋友
She's not me girlfriend.
我可不喜歡善良又普通的女人
I'm clearly not attracted to nice, normal women.
你這幾年都在忙什么呢  威爾
What have you been up to all these years, Will?
還在乞討  借錢  偷竊嗎
Still begging, borrowing, and stealing?
真了解我
Bloody hell.
也許你能騙過所有人
Maybe you've fooled all these people
讓他們相信你是什么王后
into believing you're some kind of queen...
但我知道你的真實身份
but I know who you really are...
安娜斯塔西婭
Anastasia.
你從來不知道什么時候該消停  是吧  威爾
You never did know when to stop fighting, did you, Will?
你打算把我關在這多久
How long are you gonna keep me in here?
不如先關一輩子
How about we start with forever
剩下的事以后再說
and work our way back from there?
他不在里面
He's not in there.
誰不在里面
Who's not in there?
你在找杰克  對嗎
You're looking for the knave, right?
他不在里面
He ain't in there.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
如果他在里面
'Cause if he was,
我就會在里面收取報酬了
I'd be inside collecting a reward.
你也是在追捕隊的
You're one of those collectors
你也在找他
that was chasing him.
而且很不幸  還沒抓到他
And, unfortunately, not the one catching him.
等等  有人抓到他了嗎
Wait. Did someone catch him?
我可以告訴你  但是你看啊
I could tell ya. But, you see, I got this thing
有人用劍指著我的時候
where it's hard for me to be straight with people
我很難坦言相告
pointing swords at me.
紅心王后抓到他了
The Red Queen got him.
-你確定嗎  -確定
- Are you quite sure? - Oh, yeah.
這些傷就是證據
I got the bruises to prove it.
我知道我該怎么做了
Well, I know what I have to do.
謝謝你  小姐...
Thank you, miss...
伊麗莎白
Elizabeth.
但大多數人叫我麗莎爾
But most people call me Lizard.
我叫愛麗絲
Alice.
祝我好運吧
Wish me luck.
等等  你要去追他嗎
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait. You going after him?
不  是"她"
No. I'm going after her.
紅心王后  你一個人是進不去的
The Red Queen? You can't go in there by yourself.
為什么每個人都這么說
Why does everybody keep telling me that?
因為這是事實
Maybe 'cause it's true.
好吧  管他的  我和你一起去
Fine. Hell with it. I'm coming with you.
我好像沒請你這么做
I'm quite certain I didn't ask you to.
不管怎樣
Whatever.
杰克欠我的  而且死人可不能還債
The Knave owes me, and, uh, dead men can't pay debts.
恭喜你  陛下
Congratulations, majesty.
恭喜什么
About what?
這么快就抓到了杰克
Such a quick capture of the knave.
消息傳得真快
News travels fast.
確實如此
Yes, it does, doesn't it?
我只是想問  為什么他還活著
But I just have to ask, why is he still breathing?
-你說誰  -杰克
- Pardon? - The Knave.
我知道他被你關在地牢里
I understand he's locked in your dungeon.
我只是好奇為什么
I was just curious as to why that is.
我們想要除掉他  現在他已經被除掉了
We wanted him "Removed." He's "Removed."
但把他關在暗無天日的地牢
But he's no use to us locked away
對我們毫無用處
where no one can see him.
你想讓我把他綁起來示眾嗎  沒問題
You want me to put him outside in the gallows? Fine--
我要你砍下他的頭
I want you to put his head on the chopping block!
公開處決
A public execution
這樣  每個人都會看到幫助愛麗絲的下場
So everyone will see the price for helping Alice in wonderland.
賈法爾  你難道不知道
Did it ever occur to you, Jafar,
對我們來說  讓他活著比死了更有用
that he might be more useful to us alive than dead?
對我們更有用
More use to us...
還是對你更有用
or more use to you?
你在暗示什么嗎
Do you have something to say?
你就沒事要告訴我嗎
Do you?
你先是忘了告訴我杰克在幫助愛麗絲
First you forget to tell me this knave was helping Alice,
現在你又不愿殺了他
now you seem reluctant to kill him.
這讓我不禁好奇
It makes me wonder if
你的不作為是不是另有隱情
perhaps there's a reason for your inaction.
是時候看看你是不是一個
It's time to find out if you're a woman
為得到想要的東西
who's prepared to do whatever it takes
可以不惜一切代價的女人
to get what she wants,
還是只是一個
or just a little girl
除了偷來的王冠  而一無所有的小女孩
with a stolen crown and nothing else.
這一次  讓我看清楚
Let me be clear this time.
殺了他
Kill him.
這本書包含了世間所有
This book contains all the world's wisdom
關于精靈的知識
about genies.
精靈
Genies?
這就是你一直以來拒絕與我分享的秘密
That's what you've refused to share with me all this time?
我得等到你準備好
Well, I had to wait until you were ready.
現在你準備好了
And you are.
這本書里的咒語
Inside these pages is a spell
只有擁有三只精靈的力量
that only the power of the three genies
才能施放
will allow us to cast.
這個咒語非常強大  即使是我
A spell so powerful that even I,
用上我所有的魔力  也無法獨自施展
with all my magic, could not attempt alone.
但現在我有了一個搭檔
But now that I have a partner...
什么樣的咒語會這么難
What kind of spell could be so difficult
需要我們兩個才能進行
that it requires both of us?
如果成功了
One that, if we succeed,
我們將成為世界上最強大的巫師
will make us the most powerful sorcerers the world has ever known.
我們將能改變魔法規則
We will be able to change the very laws of magic.
一旦做到這一點
And once we do that...
一切都唾手可得
all we desire will be at our fingertips.
你愿意將這一切與我分享
And you wish to share this with me?
你的慷慨
Your generosity--
我不知道該如何報答
I don't know how I could ever repay it.
我等待了無數歲月
I have waited many, many years
尋找值得這一切的人  賈法爾
to find someone worthy of this, Jafar.
就像你等待了那么多年
Just as you have waited years to seek your revenge
去向拋棄你的父親
not only on your father who cast you out,
和所有那些輕視你
but on all those who ever... belittled you...
或懷疑你的人復仇
or doubted you.
沒人對我這么友善過
No one has ever shown me such kindness.
也沒有人
No one...
像我這樣深愛你
has ever loved you like I do.
就快成功了
Almost there.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
-你說什么  -舉起你的雙手
- Excuse me? - Show me your hands.
我不懂
I don't understand.
我看到你手里拿著東西
You're holding something. I saw it.
舉起你的雙手
Show me your hands.
很好
All right.
很鋒利
Sharp.
磨了很長時間吧
Must have taken you a long time.
王后的宮殿是個陷阱密布的地方
The queen's palace is a tricky place.
我知道  我
I know. I, uh,
每半年左右就去雙胞胎兄弟那扒一次
pickpocket the tweedles every six months or so.
你從未被逮到嗎
And you never got caught?
名師出高徒嘛
Learned from the best.
-是紅桃杰克嗎  -當然了
- The Knave? - Of course.
你這么做  不是為了
You're not doing this for repayment
要追回債務吧
of a financial debt, are you?
我當時在街上
I was on the streets.
他收留了我  給我一瓦遮頭
He took me in, gave me a place to sleep.
教會了我這一身本領
Taught me everything I know.
很遺憾聽到這些
Well, sorry to hear that.
走吧  我知道他有時很難相處
Come on, I know he can be difficult,
可是他心地善良  這要謝謝你了
but his heart's in the right place, thanks to you.
聽起來你倆曾是親密好友
Sounds like you two were close friends.
除非  等等  你倆是否
Unless... wait, were you two...
不   不是
No. Uh, no.
我絕對不會
I mean... I would never...
威爾和我  我們只是一起跑路
Will and I-- we just ran together.
一起偷東西
You know, stealing.
有時是為了毛蟲
Sometimes for the Caterpillar, and...
有時只是為了好玩
sometimes just for fun.
你們以搶劫他人為樂嗎
You'd rob people for fun?
自從安娜斯塔西婭的事情之后
Will kind of went through a dark period
威爾經歷了一段黑暗的時期
after the whole Anastasia thing.
又是這個  安娜斯塔西婭
There's that name again-- Anastasia.
這個女孩到底是何方神圣
Who is this girl?
從未見過  但不管她是誰
Never met her, but whoever she is,
她都徹底毀了他
she completely wrecked him.
人們都說威爾離開仙境是因為他債臺高筑
Everyone says Will left Wonderland 'cause of his debts,
但我并不這么看
but I don't think so.
這地方令他想起她
This place reminded him of her.
我想他只是再也承受不了了
I think he just couldn't take it anymore.
你來這里干嘛
What are you doing here?
我以為成為王后的好處
I thought the whole point of becoming queen
就是再也不必親自動手做那些骯臟的勾當了
was that so you never had to get your hands dirty again.
威爾  那些勾搭還是我做
Will, I still get my hands dirty.
唯一不同的是  現在我可以讓別人
The only difference is now I get people
為我動手處理
to clean them off for me.
這么說你只是來幸災樂禍的嗎
So you've just come to gloat?
提醒你自己  多年以前
Remind yourself that you did the right thing
-所做的事都是正確的嗎  這不是原因
- all those years ago? - That's not why.
那你究竟為什么來
Then why?
我是來告訴你過幾分鐘后
I came to tell you that in a few minutes,
白兔會過來告訴你
the white rabbit will be here with instructions
離開仙境的路
to take you out of Wonderland
帶你回到他發現你的地方
and back to where he found you.
-是嗎  -威爾  我是說真的
- Will he now? - Will, I'm serious.
你這樣是為了要我逃跑  再當場逮住我嗎
Is this the part where you get to catch me escaping?
然后給自己一個殺我的借口嗎
Give you an excuse to kill me?
威爾  我不需要找借口來殺你
Will, I don't need an excuse to kill you.
我需要一個不用殺你的借口
I need an excuse not to kill you.
與我有關聯的人想要你死
I'm involved with people who want you dead.
從何時起  你開始照他人的意志來行事了
Since when did you do what anyone told ya?
不是
No.
你還不明白嗎
No, you don't understand.
我是想要彌補你
I'm trying to make it up to you.
安娜  我不需要你的同情
I don't need your pity, Anna.
事實上你需要  因為我不同情你的話
Actually, you do, because without my pity,
你將會失去很多東西  包括你的腦袋
you won't have a lot of things, including your head!
所以等兔子來的時候
So when the Rabbit gets here--
我不會走的
I'm not going.
威爾  不要犯傻了
Oh, don't be a fool now, Will.
如果我是傻子  那也是因為你
If I'm a fool, it's only because you made me one.
你是個可怕的人
You're a terrible person
對人心狠手辣
who does terrible things to people.
但是我認為有一件事  就連你也不會做
But I think there's one thing even you won't do.
是什么
What's that?
殺了我
Kill me.
事實上  我打賭你不敢殺我
In fact, I dare you to kill me.
因為在我看來  你沒這個膽量
Because personally, I don't think you've got it in ya.
你應該比任何人都清楚
You should know better than anyone
最能保證我動手的方法
that the surest way to make me do something
就是告訴我  我做不到
is to tell me that I can't.
你是做不到
You can't.
打擾一下
Excuse me.
發生什么事了
What's going on here?
馬上會有公開行刑
There's gonna be an execution.
請讓讓
Excuse me?
對不起
Pardon me?
刀劍不長眼
I have a blade.
-上面寫了什么  -紅桃杰克
- What's it say? - The Knave.
他們要處決他
They're executing him...
今日公開處決
紅桃杰克
就在今天
Today.
那輛投石車是用來做什么的
What's the Catapult for?
如果搶到頭  就有免費的晚餐
If you catch the head, you get a free dinner.
-射好點  -讓他的腦袋飛起來
- Make it a good one! - Make his head fly.
射得真棒
That was a beauty!
依舊如此野蠻
Still barbaric as ever.
為王后歡呼
Hail the queen!
我們得救威爾
We have to save Will.
你有辦法嗎  貌似已經希望全無了
You have an idea? 'Cause this is looking bleak.
砍掉他的腦袋
Off with his head!
事實上  我有辦法
As a matter of fact, I do.
殺掉紅桃杰克
Kill the Knave!
你的笑容跑哪去了
Now where's that smile?
你知道王后的樣兒
You know the one.
一看到人頭落地就會喜笑顏開
The one that loves a good beheading.
這不就是嘛
It's right here.
有什么問題嗎  合作伙伴
Anything wrong... partner?
沒問題  只是你經常干涉我處理事務
No. Just your constantly interfering with my affairs.
我認為是你的事務
I think it's your affairs
在讓我神煩
that are interfering with me.
如果你有話要說
If you've got something to say,
就快點說
spit it out.
愛麗絲來了
Alice is here.
在庭院里
In the courtyard.
叫守衛抓住她
Well, have the guards seize her.
我們不需要她來搞破壞
We don't need her ruining things--
不  只要
No. Just...
只要盯住她就行了
Just keep an eye on her.
是時候讓我們看看  她為了達到目的
It's time for us to see how far she's willing to go
愿意付出多大的代價
to get what she wants.
我們打烊了
We are closed.
我不是來喝酒的
I'm not here for a drink.
如果來尋歡  請上樓吧
If it's women you seek, then that's upstairs.
我要你手里的精靈
I want the genie in your possession.
我沒有精靈
I don't have a genie--
不必否認了
Don't bother denying it.
謠言傳千里
Rumors travel great distances, sir,
特別是那些關于魔法的流言
When magic is involved.
很抱歉  讓你千里迢迢地撲了個空
I'm sorry you've come so far for nothing.
我不準備把瓶子交出去
I'm not ready to pass on the bottle.
我還有一個未許的愿望
I still have one more wish to make,
我要留著適當的時候使用
and I'm saving it for just the right thing.
而且我不著急
And I'm in no hurry.
可是我著急
But I am.
你是誰
Who are you?
我將是你最后看到的人
The last person you will ever see
除非你交出我想要的東西
unless you give me what I want.
你瞧
You see...
我會帶著精靈離開這里
I will be leaving here with the genie.
但問題是  你還能活著離開這里嗎
The question is, will you be leaving here at all?
如果你對精靈如此感興趣
If you are so interested in genies,
那你就該知道你不能殺了我
then you know you can't kill me.
成為他的新主人的唯一方法就是
The only way for you to become his new master
讓我許下我所有的愿望
is for me to make all of my wishes.
說得對
You're right.
我是不能殺你
I can't kill you.
但我可以讓你痛不欲生
But I can inflict so much pain,
似乎沒有任何愿望值得你付出如此的代價
no wish will ever seem worth it.
我許愿你無法傷害到我
I wish that you can do me no harm.
如您所愿
As wishes go,
您真是我見過的最識時務的許愿人
that's one of the wiser ones I've heard.
雜種  滾回地溝里去吧
Go back to the gutter, you bastard.
你說什么
What did you say?
你聽到了
You heard me.
是啊  但我想再聽你說一次
Perhaps I did, but I'd like to hear you say it again.
你忘記我許下的愿望了嗎
Did you forget about my wish?
你再也傷害不了我了
You can't hurt me anymore.
的確是  但是她可以
True, but she can.
求你
Please...
不要殺我  求求你
don't kill me, I beg you.
你會明白  有些事比死亡更痛苦
I think you'll find there are far worse things than death.
現在我們還差一個瓶子了
We're now one bottle away.
敬我們倆
To us.
把紅心杰克帶上來
Bring on the Knave!
殺了他
Kill him!
殺了這個叛徒  殺了紅心杰克
Kill the traitor! Kill the Knave!
現在就砍下他的腦袋
Off with his head now!
他就該去死
He deserves to die!
讓他付出代價
Make him pay!
我要看著他的頭滾下來
I want to see his head roll!
冷靜點
Be still.
你們從不清掃這里嗎
Don't you ever clean these things?
殺了這個叛徒
Kill the traitor!
-殺了他  -馬上殺了他
- Kill him now! - Come on!
這就對了  殺了他
That's it, kill him!
讓他好好受受折磨
Make him suffer!
讓他人頭落地
Off with his head!
出什么事了
What's happening?
老天啊
Bloody hell.
阻止他們
Stop them!
攔住他們
他們想要逃跑
They're trying to escape!
別讓他們跑了
Don't let them get away!
我還以為我死定了
I thought I was bolluxed.
如果那個行刑者再高六英寸的話
If that executioner had been 6 inches taller,
你就真死定了
You would have been.
好吧
All right.
我們究竟要怎么離開這里
How the bloody hell do we get out of here?
來吧  走這邊
Come on. This way.
麗莎爾  你嚇了他一大跳
Lizard, you knocked him out cold.
你們都在想些什么啊
What were you thinking?
你們可能都會送命
You could have both been killed.
一句"謝謝"就好了
A simple "Thank you" would suffice.
謝謝
Thank you.
還有你  lizard
You, too, lizard.
走右邊  跟我來
To the right! Follow me!
有人來了
We got company.
-最好趕緊走  -在這里  快來
- We better go. - Over here! Come on!
他們在迷宮里
They're in the maze!
你好  愛麗絲
Hello, Alice.
-這家伙是誰啊  -晚點再跟你解釋
- Who the hell is that? - I'll tell you later.
我們得先逃走
We need to get out of here--
這么快就要走了嗎
Leaving so soon?
我來掩護  你們快逃
I'll distract 'em. You guys run.
麗茲  不要
Liz, no!
Lizard
Lizard!
我想是正式見面的時候了  我叫...
I suppose it's time we met. My name is--
我知道你是誰  賈法爾
I know who you are, Jafar.
塞勒斯把你的一切都告訴我了
Cyrus has told me all about you.
有意思
Interesting.
我今天也算對你有所了解了  愛麗絲
It seems I've learned a little bit about you today as well, Alice.
你了解我什么了
And what was that?
你愿意為了朋友而做任何事
That you're willing to do anything for a friend.
真讓人感動
Quite touching, actually.
停下  他什么也沒做
Stop it! He's done nothing!
拜托了  求你
Please, I beg you!
你不需要求我  愛麗絲
You don't have to beg, Alice.
許愿就行了
Just wish.
安娜斯塔西婭
Anastasia...
快許愿  愛麗絲
Just make a bloody wish, Alice!
我許愿  紅桃杰克一死
I wish if the Knave of Hearts dies...
我也會立刻死去
then I die!
不要  愛麗絲
Alice, no.
干得好  愛麗絲  干得好
Well played, alice. Well played.
你已經許下一個愿望了  還剩下兩個
That's one wish down, and two to go.
除非你殺了我
You'll have to kill me first.
等等
Oh, wait.
你還不能殺我  對吧
You can't now, can you? True.
沒錯  我需要你活著  這樣才能許愿
True. I need you alive to make your wishes.
但我不需要你完好無損
But I don't need you whole.
愛麗絲
Alice...
你只需要許愿讓我住手
All you have to do is wish for me to stop,
所有這些痛楚就會停止了
And the pain will go away.
你只需要付出說幾個字的代價
Such sweet relief can be yours
就可以得到無比甜蜜的解放
for the bargain price of a few words.
我絕不會讓塞勒斯任你擺布
I will never put Cyrus at your mercy.
你確定嗎
Are you sure about that?
你只能殺了我  賈法爾
You'll have to kill me, Jafar,
因為我永遠不會為你而許愿
'cause I will never, ever wish for you.
愛麗絲  你還好嗎
Alice... are you all right?
還好
Yes.
走吧
Come on.
趁我們還能動  趕緊離開這里
Let's get out of here while we still can.
我的確不能殺了你們中的任何一個
While it's true I might not be able to kill either of you,
但你得明白  愛麗絲
I think you'll find, Alice,
有些事比死亡更可怕
There are worse things than death.
我動不了了
Can't move.
這是怎么了
What's happening?
愛麗絲  這是怎么了
Alice, what's happening?
住手  讓他住手
Stop him. Make him stop.
你是對的  王后陛下
You were right, your majesty.
讓他活著的確比讓他死了更有用
He was more useful alive than dead.
你不會為了自己而許愿  愛麗絲
So you won't use your wishes to help yourself, Alice?
那么我就會摧毀所有你在乎的
Then I will keep destroying all the things you care about,
傷害所有你愛的人
hurting all the people you love...
直到你別無他選
until you have no other choice.
因為你有軟肋  愛麗絲
Because you have a weakness, Alice.
今天我已經看出來了
I've seen it today.
你有一顆心
You have a heart.
相信我  我會好好利用這一點的
And trust me, I shall exploit it.
幫幫他
Help him.
我為什么要幫他  親愛的
Why would I want to do that, darling?
因為你在乎他
Because you care.
你不了解我
You don't know me.
不  我了解你
Yes, I do...
安娜斯塔西婭
Anastasia.
你能夠幫助他
You can help him.
能幫助他的是你  用你的愿望
You can help him. Wish!
你要是再這樣做  親愛的  我就...
You keep on doing that, dear, and--
怎樣  殺了我  你不能
What? You'll kill me? You can't.
你以為你們占盡優勢  但事實并非如此
You think you have the advantage, but you don't.
我的朋友可沒有被變成石頭
I'm not the one whose friend has turned to stone
我的愛人也沒有被監禁
And whose love is in my possession.
現在  你可以繼續表現得像
Now... you can carry on behaving like the little girl
我們剛見面時的那個小女孩一樣
you were when we very first met.
你也可以趕緊長大
Or you can grow up.
做點符合常理的事情
And do what common sense compels you to do.
反正你知道在哪里可以找到我
Either way, you know where to find me.
你不把我關進監牢  折磨我嗎
You're not... going to put me in prison, torture me?
若我不遵照你的命令  就讓我把牢底坐穿
Let me rot until I do your bidding?
你還沒看出來嗎  親愛的
Don't you see, darling?
你已經在監牢里了
You are in prison.
不然你以為仙境是什么
What do you think wonderland is?
你是我的囊中之物  愛麗絲
You're mine, Alice.
從現在起  事情只會變得更糟
And from now on, things are only going to get worse.
直到你完成了自己的任務
Until you do what you must.
許完愿望
Wish.
相信你已經知道了
I'm sure you already know,
你的摯愛今天已許下了她的第一個愿望
But your precious love used her wish today.
你知道這意味著什么
I think you know what that means.
這個籠子很快就會沒用了
Soon the cage won't be necessary,
因為你很快就會回到你的歸屬地
Because you'll be back where you belong--
回到你的瓶子里
In your bottle.
發生什么好事了
What's the occasion?
我聽到了傳言
I've heard a rumor.
關于第三個精靈嗎
The third genie?
他就在阿格拉巴
Right here in agrabah.
為了前兩個精靈  我們長途跋涉
With how far we've traveled to get the others,
如今這個可真是讓人愉快
that would be a welcome change.
我很自信  我很快就會得到第三個精靈
I'm confident I will soon have the third genie,
然后我就可以準備好施咒了
And then I'll be ready to begin the spell.
你是說我們就可以準備好施咒了
You mean we will be ready to begin the spell.
賈法爾
Jafar?
還記得嗎  很久以前
Do you remember a long time ago,
你問過我  為了得到所求之物愿意付出什么
you asked me what I was willing to do in order to get what I want?
你做了什么
What have you done?
這是一劑可以攫取你魔力的魔藥
It's a potion to steal your magical essence.
不過估計你早就知道
But then again, you probably know that.
這正是你的書中所記錄的
It was in your book.
你是愛我的
You loved me.
不
No.
是你愛著我
You loved me.
求你  賈法爾  別這樣
Please, Jafar. Don't do this.
你一個人是完成不了這個咒語的
You know you can't complete the spell on your own.
沒有一個人可以單獨施展這么強大的力量
No one person can achieve that much power alone.
我不是一個人
I won't be alone.
我有你
I'll have you...
還有你的魔力
and your magic.
現在是時候
Now it's time for you,
像你喜愛的毒蛇那樣
like the serpent you so admire...
蛻去舊皮了
to shed your skin.
恭喜你  阿瑪拉
Congratulations, Amara.
你已經重生了
You are reborn.
你還有一半
You have the other half.
這是個傳說  你聽過關于如愿骨的傳說嗎
It's a myth, what you've heard about wishbones--
當如愿骨被一分為二時
That when you break them,
手上拿著較大那一半者將得以實現愿望
whoever has the larger half gets a wish.
這是精靈們在很久以前編造出的故事
It's a story, created long ago by genies,
目的是為了讓人們相信
to make people believe
他們不必為了滿足自己的欲望
That you did not need to seek out a bottle
而四處尋找瓶子
in order to someday have what you desire.
而直到今天
And so to this day,
人們還在不停地拆開如愿骨
people keep pulling wishbones apart,
期望有魔力從中噴涌而出
hoping that magic will spill out of them.
但如愿骨真正想要的
But what a wishbone really wants
與我們所想要的無二
is no different from what we all want.
那就是與自己的另一半重逢
To be joined to our other half.
而一旦與愛人被分離  你會盡其所能
And if we're separated, you will do whatever it takes
與愛人重聚
to be together again.
正如這支如愿骨一樣
Just like a wishbone.
仙
境
奇
緣
第一季  第四集
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
更多影視更新請登陸www.YYeTs.com
翻譯  冰藍  瀟湘月影
翻譯  如是我聞  Silence
校對  爵士年代蓬蓬裙
時間軸  冰藍  萌
后期  吉吉
總監  wdjmhs